Guide to the Cormac McCarthy Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- No Country for Old Men, 2003-2007, undated
  - Proofs, 2005
    - Page proof fragments. Various pages from March 29, 2005 proof (41 leaves); 1 loose leaf page of holograph notes, April 11 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Production Materials, 2005, undated
    - Dust jacket proof, first edition (2 copies), undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Dust jacket proof for UK (Picador) edition, plus ANS from Binky [Amanda Urban] to McCarthy, May 13, circa 2005 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Promotional placard for bookstores, plus ANS from Liz Van Hoose at Knopf to McCarthy, undated
    - Digital printouts of Cormac McCarthy portraits by photographer Derek Shapton for dust jacket consideration, plus ANS from Liz Van Hoose, April 26, 2005 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Reviews, 2005
    - Photocopies of reviews from Booklist (May 1, 2005); Publishers Weekly (May 23, 2005); and Entertainment Weekly (May 27, 2005) (Box 86, Folder 9)
- The Road, 2005-2007, undated
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, fragments, and proofs for McCarthy's 2006 Pulitzer Prize-winning novel, The Road
  - Correspondence, 2006
    - Dan Frank to McCarthy. TNS (1 leaf) plus 5 leaves proofs, March 3, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Sending Peter Andersen's text design for The Road.
    - Dan Frank to McCarthy. TNS (2 leaves) plus email print out enclosure (2 leaves), June 21, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Enclosing printout of email from Jane Daniels Lear to Dan Frank with sailor Joe McCann notes, also sending suggested corrections from McCarthy Society member.
    - Jane Daniels Lear to Dan Frank. Printout of above enclosed email (4 leaves). Pus 5 leaves of corrected typescript pages, March 21, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Dan Frank to McCarthy. TNS (1 leaf), June 28, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      Referring to previous notes and corrections.
    - Sonny Mehta to McCarthy. TNS (1 leaf). Re: jacket proofs, August 1, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Sonny Mehta to McCarthy. Facsimile (17 leaves), August 2, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Sending corrected pages from third and fourth pass proofs.
    - Sonny Mehta to [McCarthy]. Facsimile of forwarded email printout from Guido Goluke to Margaret Halton, (1 leaf), August 4, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Diana Tejerina to McCarthy. TLS (1 leaf), August 23, 2006 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      Enclosing finished copies of The Road. Discusses website URL on book jacket, and sending second pass proofs of Sunset Limited.
  - Notes, 2005, undated
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected in folder marked "Old Road Notes." 53 leaves, undated (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy pages, no holograph corrections in envelope marked "June 20 05 x'd misc. new mss." 16 leaves (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Photocopy of corrected typescript pages in folder marked "Xeroxes of 7 and 8 not mailed but carried to US." 29 leaves, undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Drafts, 2005, undated
    - Typescript draft, unnumbered pages in folder marked "The Road – 1st draft." Heavily corrected in pencil. 302 leaves, undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Typescript draft, heavily corrected in pencil. In folder marked "Road – old 2nd draft." 181 leaves plus folder. Irregular pagination, circa June 2005 (Box 87, Folder 7)
      1-48; 51-73; 71; 74; [no #]; 75-76; 40; 76; 79-85; 77-78; 86; 78-79; 88-94; 87; 95-154; 156-157; 137-143; 144a; 144b; 145-147; 160; 158; 146; 159; 163; 162; 161; 155; 145b.
    - Typescript draft, heavily corrected in pencil. 248 pages (265 leaves). Irregular pagination, circa August-September 2005 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      1-8; 9x-1; 9x-2; 9; 10; 10x-1; 10-17; 17-24; 24a; 25-26; 27a; 27b; 28-46; 46-61; 61-73; 73a; 74b; 75-84; 84-85; 86-1; 86-2; 86-3; 86-96; 97a; 97b; 98-107; 108a; 108b; 109; 109-113; 115a; 115b; 116-128; 129a; 129b; 130-135; 136a; 136b; 137-144; 145a; 145b; 146; 147a; 147b; 148-154; 154-161; 162a; 162b; 163-182; 183a; 183b; 184-223; 224a; 224b; 225-248; 248.
    - Photocopy of above corrected draft with different pagination. No holograph corrections. 267 pages (277 leaves). Irregular pagination, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
      1-10; 9-24; 24a; 25-27; 31-36; 66x; 37-73; 74a; 75b; 75-135; 136a; 136b; 137-144; 145a; 145b; 146; 147a; 147b; 148-248; 244-267.
    - Printout draft with holograph corrections in pencil. 233 pages, undated (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of printout draft with minor holograph corrections in pencil. 233 leaves plus Santa Fe Institute folder, undated (Box 89, Box 1)
    - Printout draft with minor holograph corrections in pencil. In Santa Fe Institute envelope with holograph note in pen, undated (Box 89, Folder 2)
      "Della, I'll stop in after lunch to see when you might get to this (It's very little) – Cormac"
    - Printout draft with holograph corrections in pencil. Includes three typescript pages. 231 pages (235 leaves), undated (Box 89, Folder 3)
      1-3; 3; 4-22; 22.4; 23-141; 141x; 142-203; 218; 20-231
    - Photocopy of corrected printout draft. 248 pages (245 leaves) plus Santa Fe Institute folder marked "Setting copy", undated (Box 89, Folder 4)
      1-151; 151-152; 152-158; 163-217; 219-248
    - Printout draft with minor corrections in pencil. 247 pages (249 leaves, plus Santa Fe Institute envelope), undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
      1-150; 153-162; 159-173; 175-220; 220-247.
    - Printout draft with minor corrections in pencil. 247 pages, undated (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of lightly corrected printout draft. 248 pages, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of printout draft with front matter and copyeditor's marks in red; McCarthy notes in pencil. 231 pages (239 leaves), undated (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Fragments, 2005, undated
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected. Multiple sections in folder marked "Road Rough D (shred)." 124 leaves, undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Typescript pages, heavily corrected. Random pages. 133 leaves plus folder marked "Road (p. 164-) old 2nd draft", 2005 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages; multiple titled sections. 117 leaves, undated (Box 91, Folder 3)
      p. 150-161, 12 leaves.
      p. 168-177, 10 leaves.
      p. 178-192, 15 leaves. p. 193-199, 7 leaves. p. 198x-218, 23 leaves.
      Flarepistol p. 219-225, 7 leaves.
      Flarepistol p. 219-243, 25 leaves.
      Grail, 8 leaves. LD, 3 leaves.
      Road notes, 7 leaves.
    - Photocopy of corrected pages, 18 leaves plus post-it note, undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Proofs, 2006-2007, undated
    - Setting copy marked "AU Set 1st pass 5/25." Holograph corrections in pencil. 242 pages (252 leaves), undated (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Box for proof in box 91, folder 6. Grey paper box with Alfred A. Knopf label marked "For 1st pass of The Road" (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Page proofs, 2nd pass with several missing pages. Includes June 26, 2006 cover letter from Dan Frank to McCarthy. 187 leaves (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Corrected "missing" pages from above page proofs. 71 leaves, June 22, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Page proofs, no corrections. 248 pages (256 leaves), July 14, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Box for proof in box 92, folder 3. Off-white paper box with Alfred A. Knopf label (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Page proofs for Vintage paperback edition. 1st pass. February 20, 2007 with February 22, 2007 cover letter from Diana Coglianese to McCarthy. Copy editor's queries in red; McCarthy responses in pencil. 296 pages (304 leaves), February, 2007 (Box 93, Folder 1)
- The Sunset Limited, 2006, undated
  Correspondence, drafts, fragments, proofs, and production material for McCarthy's 2006 novel in dramatic form, Sunset Limited. It was originally performed by Chicago's Steppenwolf Theatre Company.
  - Correspondence, 2006
    - Diana Tejerina to McCarthy. Facsimile. 1 leaf, July 20, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Faxing Kirkus Review (not included)
    - Diana Tejerina to McCarthy. Facsimile. 3 leaves, July 27, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Regarding sell sheet from Vintage edition. 2 copies of sell sheet included with holograph corrections by McCarthy.
    - Diana Tejerina to McCarthy. Facsimile. 1 leaf, August 10, 2006 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      Regarding Dutch translator's queries for The Road. Queries not included.
    - Three typescript pages with holograph corrections, undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Drafts, 2006
    - Typescript draft with holograph corrections in pencil. In envelope marked "Rough Draft." 155 leaves. Irregular pagination, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Photocopy of corrected early draft, 127 pages (134 leaves), undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Printout draft with holograph corrections in pencil, 86 pages (96 leaves), undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Printout draft with holograph corrections in pencil pages 1-91 (no page 86). 90 leaves, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Printout draft. No corrections. 114 pages, undated (Box 94, Folder 6)
    - Printout draft. No corrections. 114 pages in envelope marked "final", undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
    - Printout draft with some typescript pages inserted. Heavily corrected in pencil. 114 pages (124 leaves), undated (Box 94, Folder 8)
    - Printout draft. No corrections. Marked "March 20, '06" on final page. 102 pages, circa March 2006 (Box 94, Folder 9)
    - Printout draft marked "one act version (w/ 1st pencil corr's)." Holograph corrections in pencil. 106 leaves, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Printout draft marked "one act (2nd pencil corr's March '06)." Includes inserted typescript pages 63-1; 63-2 and 103. 105 pages (108 leaves), circa March 2006 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Printout draft with minor holograph corrections in pencil. Marked "last corr's." 105 leaves, undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Printout draft marked "final corrected." 105 pages, undated (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Fragments, undated
    - Printout pages with holograph corrections in pencil. Pages 1-44 (45 leaves), undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Holograph and printout pages in folder marked "Sunset - useable has been typed out." 44 leaves, undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Proofs, 2006
    - Copyedited manuscript and style sheet. Corrections in green marker and red ink. Includes memo dated June 20, 2006 and style sheet. 117 leaves. Irregular pagination (Box 95, Folder 7)
      Memo; Style Sheet; i; ii; iii; iv; v; vii; viii; ix; x; xi; 1-58; 59/60; 61-62; 63a; 63b; 64-84; 85/86/87; 88-97; 98a; 98b; 99-102; 103x; 103-105.
    - Photocopy of copyedited draft. Includes omitted pages [originally housed in the Santa Fe Institute folder]. 125 leaves, undated (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Page proofs, 1st pass with typescript page 114-b. Holograph corrections in pencil. Includes letter from Diana Tejerina to McCarthy. (153 leaves), August 7, 2006 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages from 1st pass proof. 34 leaves, undated (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Page proofs, 2nd pass with corrections in pencil and blue graphite. 152 leaves, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Page proofs, stamped "Revised Proof," no corrections, (160 leaves). Plus photocopies of corrected pages (14 leaves), undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Production Materials, 2006, undated
    - Book jacket proof, Vintage International, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Steppenwolf Theatre Company folder marked "Playwright." Includes September 7, 2006 letter; corrected script; spring 2006 season schedule; notes; calendar; note card; newspaper review (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Steppenwolf Theatre Company playbill and announcement (2 copies), undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
- Whales and Men [screenplay], circa 1983-1986
  Drafts and fragments for McCarthy's unproduced screenplay, Whales and Men.
  - Drafts, undated
    - First draft. Typescript with holograph corrections in pencil. Irregular pagination. 225 leaves, undated (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Photocopy of corrected draft. No holograph corrections. 167 leaves, undated (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Typescript draft with holograph corrections in pencil. 159 pages (184 leaves), undated (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Late draft. Photocopy of corrected draft. 139 pages (160 leaves), undated (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Final draft. Printout with no corrections. 133 pages, undated (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Final draft. Photocopy of printout draft with holograph corrections in pencil. Spiral bound. 133 pages, undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Fragments, undated
    - Photocopy of corrected pages 1-75, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages. 64 leaves, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages. 11 leaves, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
- The Passenger, 1999, 2001, 2004, undated
  Conditions Governing Access
  RESTRICTED until after publication
  Drafts and fragments for McCarthy's incomplete and unpublished novel titled "The Passenger." RESTRICTED.
  - Drafts, 1999, 2001, 2004, undated
    - "Old First Draft." Typescript and photocopy pages with holograph corrections in pencil. Irregular pagination, n.d. 221 leaves plus folder, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
      1-9; 1-2; 1; a; [no #]; 2-8; 9a; 9b; 9; 10a; [no #]; 10-16; 16a; 17-41; 40a; 40b; 42-65; 65a; 66; 66a; 60; 66-69; 77; 101; Q-5 through Q-7; 109a-c; 33; aa; kid; 17; 32a; 16; [4 no #]; she; 380; 376; 376a; 377; 282; 279; 278; 277; 276; 275; 274; 273; [square/dot]; [square/dot]x; 266; 265; 258; 257; 256; 248-255; 247; 243&244; 337; 238; 237; 236; 232; 235; 233-234; 231; 230; 226-227; 225b; 225a; 225; 224; 216; 210; 4c; 285; 4b; 4a; 1; 1-1; 193; 258; 179; 175; h; gx; f; 165; 165x; 164; 166; 163; 162; 158; 157; 154; b(c); d(e); a(b); a/c; w-1; w-2; 149; 148; 146; 141; 138; 137; 193; 134; 124; 123; 181; [no #]; 122; 120; 114; the campaign 1; the campaign; 100; 98; 97; 96; 95; 154; 91; 83; 82; 81; 79; 13xx; [no #]; 112; shack 7; 126; [circle/dot].
    - "Old 2nd Draft." Typescript and photocopy pages with holograph corrections in pencil. Includes 3 holograph leaves on spiral notebook paper. 1999, 2001, n.d. Irregular pagination. 328 leaves plus folder (Box 98, Folder 2)
      183; 183a; 184-195; 194x; 196-202; 211; [no #]; 203-206; 110; 216; 111; 111a; 219; kid (2 pages); 207-209; Tori 1b; she 2-3; she; 210-216; 216a; 217-228; 230; 232-236; 239-240; offshore drilling 1-3; 99; 241; 82; 242-249; 253-254; 254a; 255-268; x; 283; 1-c; 289; shex; she 100; Alicia; she 111; 269-279; his father; 280-287; 289-304; 304a; 305-316; [no #]; 317-319; she zap 1-3; 229; 231; [diamond]1; [diamond]2; 35x; 35; [square]2; [no #]; [no #]; 320-357; 174a; 155-156; 156a-d; 156dx; 157-158; 358-363; kid; 300-309; 364-379; 283-288; shack 1-16; 100; shack 17-21; shack 23-24; 27-28; shack 22; 101; shack x1; [no #]; shack 25-26; 128; [no #]; kline; ka-3; x; ka-2; F; Fx; [no #]; 149a; last days; E; she; Ex; 524; [3 notebook pages]; 524-535; 534x; 52x; [no #]; Tori; Jeff [5 leaves]; [no #]; 2N-1; F?; last days; -1.
  - Fragments, 2004, undated
    - Photocopy of corrected pages, 2004. (72 leaves) (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Photocopy of corrected pages, arranged in sections titled "man," "man/house," "shrink," "kid," and "Arch." (39 leaves), undated (Box 98, Folder 4)